A Guide to the Virginia State Reading Association records, 1967-2010
Library of Virginia
- Series V: Conferences, 1970-2005., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 19-23)
  - Conference, 2001 (exhibits--folder 1 of 3). (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Conference, 2001 (exhibits--folder 2 of 3). (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Conference, 2001 (exhibits--folder 3 of 3). (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Conference, 2002. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Conference, 2003. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Conference, 2004. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Conference, 2005. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Conference miscellaneous papers, no date. (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Series VI: Financial Records, 1968-2008., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 23-25)
  Financial Records, 1968-2008, contains audits, balance sheets, budgets, financial statements, ledgers, payment authorizations, receipts, reports, and other documents regarding the financial operations of the Virginia State Reading Association.
  - Budgets, 1970-1989. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Budgets, 1992-2008. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Budget proposals, 1972-1974. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Budget proposals, 1985-1986. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Budget proposals, 1991-1992 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Budget proposals, 1991-1992 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Budget proposals, 1997-1998. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Reports on examination (audits), 1970-1974. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Audit report, 1994. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's reports/financial reports, 1968-1979. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer's reports/financial reports, 1986-2003. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Financial statements, 1994-1995. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Financial statements, 1996, 1998-1999, 2003. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Trial balances and general ledgers, 1994. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Trial balances and general ledgers, 1995. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Trial balances and general ledgers, 1996-1998. (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Trial balances and general ledgers, 1998-1999, 2003. (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Balance sheet--cash basis, 1998, 2003. (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Disbursements (1975) and expenditures (1985-1986), 1975, 1985-1986. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Income and expenses, 1991-1992. (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Income report, 1992-1993. (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Revenue and expenses, 1996-1999. (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Chart of accounts, 1995. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Payment authorizations and receipts, 1996-1997. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Vendor payment analysis, 1996-1998. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Financial miscellaneous papers, 1988, 1995, 1998, 2007. (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Series VII: Committees, 1974-2003., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 25-26)
  Committees, 1974-2003, consists of ballots, brochures, correspondence, directories, flyers, forms, lists, memorandums, minutes, newsletters, objectives, recommendations, reports, rosters, and other papers detailing the organization and function of the committees of the Virginia State Reading Association. Includes the president's and state coordinator's reports.
  - President's reports, 1994, 1997. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Coordinator's reports, 1977, 1987. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Committee charges, 1989-1990. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Committee charges, 1990-1991. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Committee charges, 1994-1995. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Committee charges, 1995-1996. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Committee charges, 1998-1999. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Committee charges, 1999-2000. (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Committee charges, 2000-2001. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Administrators and Reading committee, 1985-1998. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Adult Literacy; Adult and Inter-generational Literacy committee, 1986-1998. (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Membership Committee, 1973-1989. (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Membership Committee, 1990-1999, 2003, no date. (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - IRA Membership committee,. (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Student Membership committee, 1991-1999. (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Newspapers in Education committee, 1985-1998. (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Nominations committee, 1978-1997. (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Parents and Reading committee, 1985-1990, 1995, 1998, no date. (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Professional Standards and Ethics committee, 1983-1987, 1997-1998. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Public Relations committee, 1983-1989. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Public Relations committee, 1990-1999, no date. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Publications committee, 1977-1987 (journal Reading in Virginia, newsletter). (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter committee, 1989-1990, 1995, 1998-1999, no date. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Reading in Virginia committee, 1990-1991, 1999. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Resolutions and Legislation committee (Legislative committee), 1984-1987. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Resolutions and Legislation committee (Legislative committee), 1989-2000, no date. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Scholarship committee, 1978-1979, 1989-1992, 1998-1999. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Teachers as Readers committee and Reading Teacher of the Year committee, 1992-1993, 1998-1999. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Teacher Research committee (Research committee), 1978-1999. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Young Authors committee (Literature/Young Authors committee), 1989-1990, 1998-2001. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Young Readers committee, 1983-1991, 1994. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Committees: Assessment; Bylaws; Citation and Remembrance; Conference; Evaluation; Exemplary Reading Award; Foundation; Handbook; Internal Audit; International Projects; Long Range Planning; and Mailing, 1974, 1977, 1979, 1986, 1990-1999. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Committees: Past Presidents' Advisory; Program; Special Projects; Technology and Reading Literacy; and VEMA committee, 1977, 1992-1999. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Committee miscellaneous papers, 1986-1999. (Box 26, Folder 16)
- Series VIII: Bylaws and Policies, 1970-2009., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 26-27)
  Bylaws and Policies, 1970-2003, contains bylaws, policy manuals and handbooks, and mission and goal statements of the Virginia State Reading Association.
  - Bylaws, 1970-1971, 1974-1975. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Bylaws, 1982-1983. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Bylaws, 1983, 1986. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Policy handbook, 1987. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Policy manual, 1988. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Bylaws, 1993. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Bylaws and policy manual, 1993. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - General policies, 1993. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Bylaws, 1995. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Bylaws, 1996. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Policy manual, 1996-1997. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Bylaws, 1997-1998. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Policy manual, 1998-1999. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Bylaws, 2003. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Policy manual, 2008-2009. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - General policies, no date. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Mission statements, goals, and miscellaneous papers, 1976-1998. (Box 27, Folder 14)
- Series IX: Correspondence, 1972-2003., Extent: 1 box. (Box 27)
  Correspondence, 1972-2003, contains letters discussing and detailing the operations and goals of the Virginia State Reading Association, as well as its relationship with the International Reading Association and with local councils.
  - Correspondence, 1972-1978. (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1985. (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1986. (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1989. (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1993. (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995. (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1997. (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 2003, no date. (Box 27, Folder 22)
- Series X: Job Announcements and Positions, 1995-2004., Extent: 1 box. (Box 28)
  Job Announcements and Positions, 1995-2004, contains information on the positions of administrative assistant, administrative secretary for membership, conference headquarters registrar, executive secretary, and legislative advocate.
  - Job announcements and positions, 1995-2004. (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Series XI: Directories, 1987-2009., Extent: 1 box. (Box 28)
  Directories, 1987-2009 contain contact information for board members and officers, committee chairs, local council heads, and other officials of the Virginia State Reading Association.
  - Directories, 1987-1991. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Directories, 1991-1994. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Directories, 1994-1996. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Directories, 1996-1998. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Directories, 1998-2001. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Directories, 2005-2007. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Directories, 2008-2009. (Box 28, Folder 8)
- Series XII: Local Councils., Extent: 1 box. (Box 28)
  Local Councils contain articles, brochures, conference registration forms, correspondence, flyers, newsletters, programs, reports, and other papers concerning the organization and operation of local councils.
  - Local Councils (Apple Valley, Chesapeake, Greater Washington, Hampton). (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Local Councils (Newport News, Norfolk, North Central Virginia). (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Local Councils (Piedmont, Portsmouth). (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Local Councils (Rappahannock, Richmond Area, Roanoke Valley). (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Local Councils (Shenandoah Valley, Southside, Southwestern, Suffolk). (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Local Councils (Virginia Beach, multiple councils [Hampton-Newport News-Williamsburg], general papers). (Box 28, Folder 14)
- Series XIII: Awards, Honor/Merit Council, 1986-2000., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 28-29)
  Awards and Honor/Merit Councils, 1986-2000, contains papers relating to awards both given and received by the Virginia State Reading Association, and papers relating to honor/merit designations to local councils by the Virginia Reading Association and the International Reading Association.
  - Awards and scholarships, 1986-1998. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - International Reading Association Award of Excellence, 1998-1999 (folder 1 of 4). (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - International Reading Association Award of Excellence, 1998-1999 (folder 2 of 4). (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - International Reading Association Award of Excellence, 1998-1999 (folder 3 of 4). (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - International Reading Association Award of Excellence, 1998-1999 (folder 4 of 4). (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Merit Council (VSRA), 1986-1998. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Merit (VSRA)/Honor (IRA) council, 1999-2000 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Merit (VSRA)/Honor (IRA) council, 1999-2000. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Honor council (IRA), no date. (Box 29, Folder 6)
- Series XIV: International Reading Association, 1983-1999., Extent: 1 box. (Box 29)
  International Reading Association, 1983-1999, contains brochures, catalogs, charts, correspondence, forms, newspapers, programs, minutes, statements, and other papers concerning the International Reading Association. The Virginia State Reading Association is an affiliated council.
  - Minutes, 1983-1984, 1986. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Papers, 1972-1976, 1982-1987. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Papers, 1988, 1992, 1994-1995. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Papers, 1996-1997, 1999. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Papers, no date. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Conferences: 12th World Congress on Reading; Southeastern Regional Conferences; Eastern Regional Conferences; College Reading Association Conference; general conference). (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Reading Today, IRA newspaper, 1987, 1991, 1993. (Box 29, Folder 13)
- Series XV: Publications, 1969-2006., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 30-31)
  Publications, 1969-2006, consist of Virginia State Reading Association newsletter, Reading in Virginia journal, Journal of the Virginia College Reading Educators, GWRC Journal, and brochures.
  - Newsletter, 1969, 1972-1973, 1975-1976, 1978. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Newsletter, 1983-1987. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Newsletter, 1990-1992, 1995, 1997. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Newsletter, 2000-2002. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter, 2003-2004. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Newsletter, 2004, 2006. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Reading in Virginia volume XIII (special edition edited by the Greater Washington Reading Council), 1988. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Reading in Virginia volume XV, 1990. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Reading in Virginia volume XXI, 1996. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Reading in Virginia volume XXII, 1997-1998. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Reading in Virginia volume XXIII, 1998-1999 (2 copies). (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Reading in Virginia volume XXV, 2000-2001 (2 copies). (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Reading in Virginia volume XXVI, 2001-2002 (2 copies). (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Reading in Virginia volume XXVII, 2003-2004 (2 copies). (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Journal of the Virginia College Reading Educators, 1983, 1990. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - GWRC Journal volume XXII (Greater Washington Reading Council), 1997-1998. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Brochures. (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Series XVI: General Subjects., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 31-32)
  General subjects contain articles, artwork, books, directories (non-organization), essays, guidelines, notebooks, packets, position papers, programs, proposals, and other papers. Includes tote bag and magnets.
  - The Advisory Board on Teacher Education and Licensure's Proposal to Revise Licensure Regulations for School Personnel. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Anguished English: An Anthology of Accidental Assaults upon our Language by Richard Lederer. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Degrees of Reading Power as Virginia's Passport to Literacy.. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Developing a Whole Language Program for a Whole School by Joanne Yatvin. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Early Intervention Reading Initiative Workshop,1997. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - FLAIR: Families Learning: Activities in Reading,2 March 1997. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Language Arts Standards of Learning,10 January 1995. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Legislative positions. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Literary Debate: Online R U Really Reading? (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Most Likely to Succeed. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Put Reading First: The Research Building Blocks for Teaching Children to Read. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Reading Redefined: A Michigan Reading Association Position Paper,1986. (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Robert's Rules of Order section, 1990. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Standards of Quality,1990. (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Standards for Reading Professionals,1998. (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Virginia English Bulletin, vol. 57, no. 1 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Vision 2000,1992. (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - What Do Parents Want to Know About Early Literacy Programs? (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Directories (non-organization): directory of speakers, directory of Virginia Bookmen's Association, Writers in Virginia Directory. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Literacy Lottery. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Department of Education. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Helms-Briscoe meeting procurement packet. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Words Alive: reading packet. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - VSRA General Assembly packet, 2002. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - VSRA regions map. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - USA Today education packet. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1973, 1976. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1980, 1986, 1988-1989. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1993-1999. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 2000-2001. (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous papers, no date. (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Placards, stationery. (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, July-September 1995. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, November 1995-January 1996. (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Tote bag and magnets. (Box 32, Folder 17)